(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T01:14:09.692658",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
よろしくおねがいします！
Thank you, let's have a great time!
どうだっていい事を 嘘って吐いて戻れない
I only know how to lie, I can't take it back now.
時効なんてやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
No statute of limitations comes, stolen as I stole.
今日だって叶わない 思ったように騙せない
Even today nothing comes true, I can't fool as I wish.
腐っている僕には 腐ったものが理解できない
To a rotten person like me, rotten things make no sense.
おいでココマデ ステイ
Come on up to here, stay...
“隠して仕舞ったんだ”
"I've hidden it away..."
メーデー 僕と分かっても 抱き締めなくていいんだよ
Mayday, even if you know it's me, you needn't hold me.
ヘイ メーデー 僕が分かったら もう一度笑ってくれるかな
Hey mayday, if you know it's me, will you smile once more?
守護したって知るんだよ
You'll know it was protected, right?
嘘つきだって知るんだよ
You'll know I'm a liar.
どうだっていい発作が キョトってYESを声に出す
A careless seizure voices a blank 'YES'.
後悔の塞欲は 回したほうが正義なの
Turning away regrets is the right thing to do.
卑怯だって叶わない 祈って置いてそれは無い
Cowardice gets nowhere, praying and leaving it won't do.
飾っていた鏡舌が 墓穴を掘って焼ける様
Like a deceitful tongue digging its own grave and burning.
おいでココマデ 負い目ど灰色
Come on up to here, burdened and grey...
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ 正直者が夢見たなら
Mayday, scold me, if an honest person dared to dream.
ヘイ メーデー 僕を裁いてよ 最後まで甘えてしまうのは
Hey mayday, judge me, for giving in till the end.
亡霊だって知るんだよ
You'll know I'm a phantom.
空虚だって知るんだよ
You'll know I'm a void.
足りないものが望んだら 僕じゃない僕に出会ったよ
When my lacking self wished for it, I met someone who wasn't me.
それでも前に進んだの クララしちゃう夜も
Yet I still kept moving forward, even on dizzy nights.
足りない僕を愛してよ 目謀ままが僕を育てたの
Love my imperfect self, caprice is what raised me.
君には僕が見えるかな
Can you see me now?
どうだっていいことを嘘って吐いて戻れない
Whatever you want to say, just tell your lies and spit them out.
時効なんてやってこない
There's no such thing as the statute of limitations.
奪ったように奪われて
As if you had stolen and been stolen from,
もう一度嘲笑ってくれるかな
I wish I could laugh at it all one more time.
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ
Mayday! If you find out that it's me,
正直者が夢見たいなら
All an honest person wants is to dream.
メーデー 僕を暴いてよ
Mayday! If you find out that it's me,
もうすぐ終わるこの世界から
From this world that is about to end,
メーデー 僕と踊ってよ
Mayday! Dance with me,
最初からいないと分かってた
Knowing from the start that you weren't real.
ピエロだって知るんだよ
I know it's just a clown show.
嘘つきだって知るんだよ
I know it's all a pack of lies.
亡霊だって知るんだよ
I know it's just a phantom.
空白だって知るんだよ
I know it's just an empty space.
どうだっていいことを嘘って吐いて戻れない
Whatever you want to say, just tell your lies and spit them out.
時効なんてやってこない
There's no such thing as the statute of limitations.
奪ったように奪われて
As if you had stolen and been stolen from.
沈むように溶けていくように
It's like we're sinking, it's like we're melting,
二人だけの空が広がる夜に
into a night where the sky spreads just for the two of us.
「さよなら」だけだった
It was just a simple "goodbye,"
その一言で全てが分かった
that one word told me everything.
日が沈み出した空と君の姿 フェンス越しに重なっていた
The sinking sun and your figure were overlapping beyond the fence.
初めて会った日から
Ever since the first day we met,
僕の心の全てを奪った
you stole all of my heart.
どこか儚い空気を纏う君は
Wrapped in a fragile air,
寂しい目をしていたんだ
you had a lonely gaze.
いつだってチックタックと鳴る世界で何度だってさ
Again and again in a world ringing with tick-tocks,
触れる心ない言葉うるさい声に涙が零れそうでも
over touching, heartless words and irritating voices,
ありきたりな喜びきっと二人なら見つけられる
ordinary happiness is something we can surely find together.
騒がしい日々に笑えない君に思い付く限り眩しい明日を
For the never-smiling you amidst the noisy days,
明けない夜に落ちていく前に僕の手を掴んでほら
please take my hand before we fall into the sleepless night.
忘れてしまいたくて閉じ込めた日々も抱きしめた温もりで溶かすから
I'll melt away the days you locked away wanting to forget
怖くないよいつか日が昇るまで二人でいよう
with the warmth of my embrace, so don't be afraid.
君にしか見えない何かを見つめる君が嫌いだ
I hate you looking at something only you can see,
見惚れているような恋するようなそんな顔が嫌いだ
like you're captivated or in love—I hate that expression.
信じていたいけど信じられないことそんなのどうだっていいってきっと
I want to believe, yet I can't believe it—
これからだっていくつもあってそのたび怒って泣いていくの
we'll surely understand each other someday.
もう嫌だって疲れたんだよなんて出掛けに差し伸べた僕の手を振り払う君
"I'm sick of this, I'm tired,"
もう嫌だって疲れたんだよなんて本当は僕も言いたいんだ
to tell the truth, I wanted to say that too.
君のために用意した言葉どれも届かない
None of the words I prepared for you reach you.
終わりに出したいなんてさ連れて言葉にした時
When I followed along and said, "I want to end it all,"
君は初めて笑った
you smiled for the very first time.
騒がしい日々に笑えなくなっていた僕の目に映る君は綺麗だ
You were truly beautiful in my eyes,
明けない夜にこぼれた涙も君の笑顔に溶けていく
and your smile melted the tears overflowing in the endless night.
沈むように溶けていくように染み付いた霧が晴れる
It's like we're sinking, it's like we're melting,
忘れてしまいたい...
as the lingering fog clears away.
沈むように溶けていくように
It's like we're sinking, it's like we're melting,
二人だけの空が広がる夜に
On that night where the sky stretched endlessly,
「さよなら」だけだった
It was only a simple "goodbye,"
その一言で全てが分かった
But it was all I needed to understand.
日が沈み出した空と君の姿
The sinking sun and your figure
フェンス越しに重なっていた
Were overlapping beyond the fence.
初めて会った日からもどかしい気持
Ever since the first day we met,
僕の心の全てを奪った
You stole all of my heart.
どこか儚い空気を纏う君は
Wrapped in some sort of fragile air,
寂しい目をしていたんだ
You had a lonely gaze.
生活の偽造
Forgery of life,
いつも通り通り過ぎて
passing by as usual.
一回言った「わかった」戻らない
I said once, "Understood," no going back.
確信犯でしょ
You knew what you were doing, right?
夕食中に泣いた後君は笑ってた
After crying during dinner, you were smiling.
「私もそうだよ」って
"I'm the same," you'd say,
偽りの気持ちかまして
faking our feelings together.
吐いて黙ってずっと溜まってく
Spitting it out, staying silent, it just piles up.
何が何でも
No matter what happens,
面と向かって「さよなら」する資格もないままで
we don't even have the right to face each other and say goodbye.
僕は灰に潜り秒針を噛む
I dive into the ash and bite the second hand.
白昼夢の中でガングン砕いた
Crushed to pieces inside a daydream.
でも壊れない止まってくれない
But it won't break, it won't stop.
「本当」を知らないまま進むのさ
Moving forward without ever knowing the truth.
このまま奪って隠して忘れたい
I want to take it as it is, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う一つもなくても
Even without a single thing we understand about each other,
会って「ごめん」って返さないでね
meeting and saying "sorry," don't return it.
形のない言葉はいらないから
Because I don't need intangible words.
消えない後遺症
An unforgettable aftereffect.
「何でも受け入れる」と言ったきりもう帰ることはない
Saying "I'll accept anything" and never returning,
君のためじゃなくても
Even if it's not for your sake,
君に守られた
I was protected by you.
目も口も意味がないほどに
To the point where eyes and mouth have no meaning,
塞ぎ込んで動けない僕らは
we are blocked and unable to move.
どこ見てもどこに居ても開かない
No matter where I look or where I am, it won't open.
肺に潜り秒針を噛む
Dive into the lungs and bite the second hand.
白昼夢の中でガングン砕いた
Crushed to pieces inside a daydream.
でも壊れない止まってくれない
But it won't break, it won't stop.
演じ続けるのなら
If you keep on acting,
このまま奪って隠して忘れたい
I want to take it as it is, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う一つもなくても
Even without a single thing we understand about each other,
会って「ごめん」って返さないでね
meeting and saying "sorry," don't return it.
形のない言葉はいらないから
Because I don't need intangible words.
叫んで叫んで朝はない
Screaming and screaming, there is no morning.
笑って転んで情けなし
Laughing and falling down, so pathetic.
誰かのせいでもないこと
It's not anyone's fault,
誰かのせいにしたくて
though I want to blame someone.
僕って居るのかな
Do I even exist?
本当は分かってるんだ
Actually, I already know.
見放されても信じてしまうよ
Even if I'm abandoned, I still believe.
生活の偽造
Forgery of life,
いつも通り通り過ぎて
passing by as usual.
一回言った「わかった」戻らない
I said once, "Understood," no going back.
確信犯でしょ
You knew what you were doing, right?
夕食中に泣いた後君は笑ってた
After crying during dinner, you were smiling.
「私もそうだよ」って
"I'm the same," you'd say,
偽りの気持ちかまして
faking our feelings together.
吐いて黙ってずっと溜まってく
Spitting it out, staying silent, it just piles up.
何が何でも
No matter what happens,
面と向かって「さよなら」する資格もないままで
without even the right to face each other and say goodbye.
僕は灰に潜り秒針を噛む
I dive into the ash and bite the second hand.
白昼夢の中でガングン砕いた
Crushed to pieces inside a daydream.
でも壊れない止まってくれない
But it won't break, it won't stop.
「本当」を知らないまま進むのさ
Moving forward without ever knowing the truth.
このまま奪って隠して忘れたい
I want to take it as it is, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う一つもなくても
Even without a single thing we understand about each other,
会って「ごめん」って返さないでね
meeting and saying "sorry," don't return it.
形のない言葉はいらないから
Because I don't need intangible words.
消えない後遺症
An unforgettable aftereffect.
「何でも受け入れる」と言ったきりもう帰ることはない
Saying "I'll accept anything" and never returning,
君のためじゃなくても
Even if it's not for your sake,
君に守られた
I was protected by you.
目も口も意味がないほどに
To the point where eyes and mouth have no meaning,
塞ぎ込んで動けない
we are blocked and unable to move.
僕らはどこ見てもどこに居ても開かない
No matter where we look or where we are, it won't open.
肺に潜り秒針を噛む
Dive into the lungs and bite the second hand.
白昼夢の中でガングン砕いた
Crushed to pieces inside a daydream.
でも壊れない止まってくれない
But it won't break, it won't stop.
演じ続けるのなら
If you keep on acting,
このまま奪って隠して忘れたい
I want to take it as it is, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う一つもなくても
Even without a single thing we understand about each other,
会って「ごめん」って返さないでね
meeting and saying "sorry," don't return it.
形のない言葉はいらないから
Because I don't need intangible words.
叫んで叫んで朝はない
Screaming and screaming, there is no morning.
笑って転んで情けなし
Laughing and falling down, so pathetic.
誰かのせいでもないこと
It's not anyone's fault,
誰かのせいにしたくて
though I want to blame someone.
僕って居るのかな
Do I even exist?
本当は分かってるんだ
Actually, I already know.
見放されても信じてしまうよ
Even if I'm abandoned, I still believe.
幽閉 利口 逝く 前 に
Locking up the clever one before they die,
ユーヘイ じゃあ 利口 に 難儀 だ ダーリン
you, hey, you know that it's a pain to get you to be obedient, darling.
幽閉 ストップ 知っ て ない し
Don't lock me up! It's not like I knew.
勘弁 に し とい て なんて 残念
Give me a break! You're so cruel.
人様 願う 欠片 の アイロニー
The wishes of the people feel like scraps of irony,
誰も が 願う 無機質 な よう な
everyone's wishing for the same mechanical thing.
一歩 足 先 に 始めて たい よう な
Wanting to get in on it before everyone else,
先 が 見え ない バージン ハッピー ショー
where nobody knows what's going to happen next in this virgin happy show.
無いの あなた に お願い 一つ
I have just one request for you:
今 も 変わら ず おまけ に マニマニ
unchanging as always, and on top of that, mani-mani.
無いの あなた に お願い 一つ
I have just one request for you:
張り詰め た 想い 込めれ
packed full of intense feelings,
レフト サイド ライト サイド
left side, right side,
歯 を 剥き出し て パッ パッ パ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa.
レフト サイド ライト サイド
Left side, right side,
歯 を 突き出し て パッ パッ パッ
let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa-pa!
はぁ 、You are king
Haha, you are king!
You are king
無邪気 に 遊ぶ 期待 期待 の ダーリン ダーリン
Playing innocently, you're the darling I've been wishing for.
健気 に 笑う 痛い 痛い の 消える
When you laugh admirably, all of my pain disappears.
無様 に しねる 苦い 思い も なく なっ て
And I'm able to die clumsily, my bitter feelings fading too.
ラララ ブウ ラッタッタ
La-la-la, buu, ratatta!
嫌い 嫌い の 最低 泣い て ダウン
I hate it, I hate it, it's the worst – I burst into tears and I'm down!
毎度 新た に お願い 一つ
Just as always, here's a brand-new wish:
今 も 変わら ず ピックアップ の まにまに
the same as ever, picking up as we go.
無いの あなた に お願い 一つ
I have just one request for you:
張り詰め た 想い 込めれ
packed full of intense feelings,
レフト サイド ライト サイド
left side, right side,
歯 を 剥き出し て パッ パッ パ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa.
レフト サイド ライト サイド
Left side, right side,
歯 を 突き出し て パッ パッ パッ
let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa-pa!
はぁ 、You are king
Haha, you are king!
You are king
みんな ！ ありがとう ！
Everyone! Thank you!
みんな 、 ありがとう ！
Thank you everyone!
という こと で 、 ゲスト に 来 て くれ まし た 、 同期 の 常闇 トワ と 桐生 ココ でーす ！
So, our guests who came today are our generation mates, Tokoyami Towa and Kiryu Coco!
おめでとう ！ やったー ！
Congratulations! Yay!
初めて ね 、 ３人 で ダンス し た けど 、 めっちゃ 楽し かっ た ！
It's our first time dancing together as three, and it was so much fun!
わちゃわちゃ 感 が ね 、 ４期生 って 感じ だ な 。
The chaotic vibe really feels like the 4th generation.
みんな びっくり し た ん じゃ ない か な 、 この ２人 が 来 て くれる って 。
I bet everyone was surprised that these two came.
まあ ね 、 ４期生 は ね 、 やっぱり ４期生 は ね 、 あの 。
Well, the 4th gen is, you know, the 4th gen is...
よっしゃ 、 全員 ね 、 そろそろ トワ も ね 、 ルーン も ね 、 明日 、 明後日 か な ？
Alright, everyone, Towa and Luna's [3D] are tomorrow and the day after, right?
ライブ を 迎え ます ので 。
You'll have your live streams coming up.
あ 、 そうそう ！
Ah, that's right!
これ から も ４期生 頑張っ て いき たい と 思い ます ので 、 皆さん 応援 よろしく お願い し ます ！
We'll keep doing our best as the 4th generation, so everyone please support us!
お 願い し まー す ！
Please do!
ありがとう ！
Thank you!
よし 、 じゃあ また ね 、 みんな で 歌お う な 。
Alright, let's all sing together again sometime.
歌お う 、 今度 は ４期生 みんな で 、 トワ と ココ と は さ 、 ２０２１年 初めて ...
Let's sing, next time with all 4th gen. Towa and Coco and I, in 2021 for the first time...
最初 に 歌っ た 歌 だって 、 ほら 、 歌い 始め 、 歌い 始め ！
The first song we sang together, look, the beginning of the year, start singing!
歌い 始め ！ ありがとう ！
Start of the year! Thank you!
あけましておめでとうございます ！
Happy New Year!
よろしく お願い し ます ！
Best regards!
やっほー ！
Yahoo!
本当 に おめでとう だ ね ！
It's really something to celebrate!
ねえ 、 １月 早かっ た ！
Man, January went by so fast!
また 今年 も 頑張り たい と 思い ます 。 なあ ？ よろしく ！
We want to do our best again this year. Right? Please look after us!
よろしく ね ！
Please do!
トワ と ココ でした 。 ちょっと 物足りない けど 、 ありがとう ！
That was Towa and Coco. It feels a bit short, but thank you!
あなた の ステージ だ から ね 。
Because it's your stage.
そう だ ね 。 主役 ！
That's right. The protagonist!
主役 ！
The protagonist!
ありがとう ！ バイバーイ ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
なんか ポーズ 取っ とこ よ 。 バイバーイ ！
Let's strike a pose. Bye-bye!
バイバーイ ！ はき ちょっと 。
Bye-bye! A little hug.
ありがとう ！
Thank you!
トワ 、 頑張って ね ！
Towa, do your best!
ありがとう ね 、 また ね ！ バイバーイ ！
Thank you, see you later! Bye-bye!
という こと で ゲスト で ね 、 トワ と ココ が 来 て くれ まし た 。
So, Towa and Coco came as guests.
いや 、 本当に 本当に 嬉しい 。 この 前 の ね 、 あの 炎上 に なっ ちゃっ た 日 も 、 あの ２人 は ね 、 来 て くれ て 一緒 に 練習 を ね 、 し て くれ まし た 。
I'm really, really happy. On that day previously when things flared up, those two came and practiced together with me.
本当に 本当に 、 あの 同期 の みんな 、 今日 は ね 一緒 に は 歌え なかっ た けど 、 まとめ と ルーン も 、 え 、 かけがえ の ない 一緒 、 大切な 仲間 だ と 思っ て い ます ので 、 ４期生 の こと これから も よろしく お願い し ます ！
Truly, all of my 4th gen peers—even though we couldn't sing together today, Matometo, Luna, and everyone—I consider them irreplaceable and precious comrades, so please continue to support the 4th generation!
それでは 次の 曲 ...
Now then, the next song...
まいりましょうか
Shall we get started?
よし、それではステージちょっと移動しちゃおうかな。
Alright, then let's move the stage a little.
えっ！
Ei!
あ、きたきたきたきた！
Ah, it's here, it's here!
それではこちらにて歌わせていただきたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to perform a song here.
本日、えーと22時ですね、この後この配信が終わった後22時15分に投稿されます、歌ってみたを歌わせていただきました、アウトサイダー歌いたいと思います！
Today, right after this stream ends at 22:15, a cover I sang of "Outsider" will be posted, so I'd love for you to check it out!
ねえねえ この世界を
Hey, hey, in this world,
どこかでひっくり返したくて
wanting to turn it upside down somewhere,
せいぜい 時間なんてありはしないが
though there's barely any time,
まあまあ そんなんで少年少女揃いまして
well, whatever, boys and girls gathered together,
語り始めた会心劇さ
beginning a masterpiece of a story.
天才で人外で横暴な
A genius, inhuman, and overbearing,
最低で最高な相棒さ
the worst and best partner.
単純で明快な考えが
A simple and clear thought
僕をここで目覚ませてくれないか
won't wake me up right here?
今この身をもって重石をとって
Taking this body now, removing the heavy burden,
君にだけにしかできないことはなんだ
what is the one thing only you can do?
慰めなんていらないよ 荒地になってしまぬように
I don't need any comfort so it won't become a wasteland,
その名を隠して ここに現れたのさ
hiding that name, appearing here.
のさばってる奴らを 探して揺すって
Sifting through the mess, searching and shaking them up,
吠えては泣いて
screaming and weeping,
勝手になって文句ばっか
making up complaints on your own.
ああ フラッシュバックして
Flashing back with panic,
感情も根性も 腐ってしまいました
emotions and roots have rotted away.
思い出したくない一日を
A day I'd rather forget
ここに吐いてってしまえよ
let's vomit it out right here.
いらんもんなんて捨ててっ和 僕をここで壊してくれないか
Throw away all the unnecessary things and break me down here!
今別れを待って
Waiting for the final farewell,
口を結んで
lips sealed tight.
染み付いた夜の傷が癒せないのなら
If the staining scars of the night cannot heal,
涙は見せないで
don't show me your tears,
こんな恥なんていらないよ
you don't need such embarrassment.
全て失ってしまぬように
So that you lose everything,
変わらぬものが此処にあるとするならば
if something unchanging remains in this place,
夜が明ける前に そうさ行っちまってくれと
let's make sure it happens before dawn breaks.
白と黒の色のない世界に溢れた
Overflowing into a world without white or black,
愛もないよ嘘の世界に塗れた
tainted in a world with no love at all.
心の鬼は決して許してはくれないから
The demon in my heart will never forgive me.
影は伸びきって 日は落ちきって
Shadows stretch out and the sun sets,
明日を迎えることが許されたなら
if I'm allowed to welcome tomorrow,
救われてたかな
would I have been saved?
それでも僕は
Even so, I will...
今この身をもって重石をとって
Taking this body now, removing the heavy burden,
君にだけにしかできないことはなんだ
what is the one thing only you can do?
慰めなんていらないよ 荒地になってしまぬように
I don't need any comfort so it won't become a wasteland,
その名を隠して ここに現れたのさ
hiding that name, appearing here.
のさばってる奴らを 探して揺すって
Sifting through the mess, searching and shaking them up,
吠えては泣いて
screaming and weeping,
勝手になって文句ばっか
making up complaints on your own.
ああ フラッシュバックして
Flashing back with panic,
感情も根性も 腐ってしまいました
emotions and roots have rotted away.
思い出したくない一日を
A day I'd rather forget
ここに吐いてってしまえよ
let's vomit it out right here.
いらんもんなんて捨ててっ和 僕をここで壊してくれないか
Throw away all the unnecessary things and break me down here!
今別れを待って
Waiting for the final farewell,
口を結んで
lips sealed tight.
染み付いた夜の傷が癒せないのなら
If the staining scars of the night cannot heal,
涙は見せないで
don't show me your tears,
こんな恥なんていらないよ
you don't need such embarrassment.
全て失ってしまぬように
So that you lose everything,
変わらぬものが此処にあるとするならば
if something unchanging remains in this place,
夜が明ける前に そうさ行っちまってくれと
let's make sure it happens before dawn breaks.
フィクサー
Fixer
今日までの記憶の 全部を消してしまう時まで
Until the time erases all memories up until today,
眠れない あしたから生きていく
I can't sleep, living on from tomorrow.
自分の身代わりが欲しくて
Wanting a substitute for myself,
今日までの記憶の 全部を消してしまう時まで
Until the day I erase all memories up until today,
眠れない あしたから生きていく
I'll live on from tomorrow, unable to sleep.
自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I desperately want a substitute for myself.
大丈夫と言わせてはくれないか
Won't you let me say "I'll be fine"?
後から君のせいにしてはくれないか 今更意味ないから
Won't you let me blame you later? Because it's meaningless now.
後から君のせいにしてはくれないか 出来ない約束を
Won't you let me blame you later for promises I couldn't keep?
とうとう溢れる 一言一言ばかりに 脳を奪われるくらい
Overflowing at last, word by word, enough to steal my mind.
意味を成さない 何も出来ない
Making no sense, unable to do anything.
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい 辞めたい
Can't see, want to run, want to fly, want to quit.
さらさら いいから 沈め 沈め
Oh well, whatever, sink, sink!
這い上がれないほどまで 飽きるまで 落とせ 落とせ
Until I can't climb back up, until I'm bored, drop me down!
救い垂らす時まで
Until salvation is cast down.
嘘臭い粒々を 喉から搾り出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
Chewing up fake granules along with screams squeezed from my throat.
笑顔が苦手なばっかで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
Just because I'm bad at smiling, I get by following familiar tones.
今日役立つ 眠たい眠たい 理想で救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by sleepy, sleepy ideals useful today.
一番目は「い」の口で言う
The first is said with an "ee" mouth shape.
力強く 固く 痛く 噛み締め
Strongly, firmly, painfully biting down.
死んでしまえ しまえ
Just die already!
この先も過去も知らず
Knowing neither future nor past.
嫌いなら 壊せ 壊せ
If you hate it, break it, break it!
どうせなら加害者になればいい
Might as well become the perpetrator.
食べきれない棘立ちも 何も生まれない悲しみも
Unfinishable thorns, sorrows that breed nothing,
味気なくて吐き出す前に
before spitting them out tastelessly,
もう もう 次を歌え
sing the next song already!
沈め 沈め 落とせ 落とせ
Sink, sink, drop, drop!
踊り踊れ 灰色になり切る前に
Dance, dance, before turning entirely to ash.
打ち鳴らせ 変われ 変われ
Ring out, change, change!
眠り落ちる時まで 奪え 奪え
Until falling asleep, take, take!
飼い慣らした嘘暴いて 煮え滾る頭に過ぎ去った虚像を見ていた
Exposing tamed lies, seeing past phantoms in my boiling head.
嘘臭い粒々を 喉から搾り出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
Chewing up fake granules along with screams squeezed from my throat.
笑顔が苦手なばっかで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
Just because I'm bad at smiling, I get by following familiar tones.
今日役立つ 眠たい眠たい 理想で救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by sleepy, sleepy ideals useful today.
一番目は「い」の口で言う
The first is said with an "ee" mouth shape.
力強く 固く 痛く 噛み締め
Strongly, firmly, painfully biting down.
死んでしまえ しまえ
Just die already!
この先も過去も知らず 嫌いなら 壊せ 壊せ
Knowing neither future nor past; if you hate it, break it!
どうせならがしゃになればいい
Might as well become outcasts.
ため息れない 苛立ちも 何も生まれない悲しみも
Irritation I can't even sigh out, and sorrows born from nothing,
味気なくて吐き出す前に もう もう 次を歌え
before spitting them out tastelessly, sing the next song already!
沈め 沈め 落とせ 落とせ 踊り踊れ
Sink, sink, drop, drop, dance, dance,
灰色になり切る前に 打ち鳴らせ 変われ 変われ 眠り落ちる時まで
before turning entirely to ash. Ring out, change, change, until falling asleep!
アディショナルメモリー 作詞・作曲: じん
[Title: Additional Memory / Music & Lyrics: Jin]
浮かんで 転げ落ちて 出会ったエンドロール
Floating up, tumbling down, meeting the end roll.
歪んだ 変わり果てた 未来の走馬灯 もうおしまいね
A distorted, utterly changed lantern of the future's memories. It's already over.
幕の切れてしまった 白昼夢は ただただ 虚しさを誤魔化して見せた
The daydream whose curtain has fallen just tried to mask the emptiness.
思い出してしまう 夕焼ける空
I end up remembering the sunset sky,
滲むメロディ 「帰ろう、道を間違えないように」
the blurring melody. "Let's go home, so we don't take the wrong road."
懦弱になって ぎゅっと繋いだ手を 宙に向けて
Growing cowardly, holding the tightly clasped hands up toward the sky...
贅沢な走馬灯
A lavish revolving lantern...
夕凪の向こうに
Beyond the evening calm,
恋を認めたためて火を灯す
I confess my love and light a flame.
過ぎ去っていく
Fading away,
腐っていく溶かした本音は
rotting away, my melted true feelings—
存在証明を跨いでしまったひとり
I was all alone, stepping over my proof of existence.
「あたし」なんてさ
"I" shouldn't have...
「言いたくなかったな」
I didn't want to say that.
拭えない涙も言葉も嘘嘘
Tears I couldn't wipe, and words, were all lies.
友達なんかになりたくなかったな
I never wanted to become just friends.
きっと届かないよな
It surely won't reach you, huh?
ごめんね 大好きだよ
I'm sorry. I love you.
これが勘違いなら
If this is a misunderstanding,
知りたくなかったな
I didn't want to know.
溢れ出る涙とか 空に吸い込まれる
Overflowing tears and such are sucked into the sky.
もう戻れないのに
Even though I can't go back,
もう感じないのに
even though I can't feel it anymore,
今さらずくんだよ
it aches so much now.
逆様になったまま
Remaining upside down.
散っていった走馬灯
A scattering revolving lantern...
夕凪の向こう
Beyond the evening calm,
想いを染めた紅の詩
a crimson poem dyeing my thoughts.
削れないでいて覚えていて残した本音は
Don't wear away, remember the true feelings left behind—
幸せを跨いでしまったひとり
I was all alone, stepping over happiness.
友達なんかで終わりたくなかったな
I didn't want it to end as just friends.
届かない涙が空に吸い込まれる
Unreachable tears are sucked into the sky.
これが勘違いでも
Even if this is a misunderstanding,
even if this is a misunderstanding,
ずっと言いたかったの
I always wanted to say it.
さよなら 大好きだよ
Goodbye. I love you.
逃げ出した夜の往来 行方は未だ不明
Fled onto the night's traffic, destination still unknown.
回り回って虚しくって 困っちゃったワンワンワン
Going in circles and feeling empty, what a dilemma, woof woof woof!
失ったつもりもないが 何か足りない気分
I don't feel like I lost anything, but something's missing.
ちょっと変にハイになって 吹き込んだ四輪車
Getting strangely high, blowing into a four-wheeler.
兄弟よ如何かしよう
Oh brother, what should we do?
もう何も考えない様
Let's not think about anything anymore.
銀河系の外へと
Beyond the galaxy,
さようなら
farewell!
真実も 道徳も 動作しない イカれた夜でも
Even on a crazy night where neither truth nor morals work,
僕ら手を叩いて笑い合う 誰にも知られないまま
we clap our hands and laugh together, known to no one.
たった一瞬の このきらめきを
This sparkle of a single moment—
食べ尽くそう二人でくたばるまで
let's devour it together until we drop,
そして幸運を 僕らに祈りを
and offer a prayer of good fortune for us!
まだ行こう
Let's go further,
誰も追い付けないくらいのスピードで 稲妻の様に生きていたいだけ
living like lightning at a speed no one can catch up to.
お前はどうしたい?
What do you want to do?
返事はいらない
No reply is needed.
転がした車窓と情景 動機は未だ不明
Rolling window scenery, motive still unknown.
邪魔臭くて芳しくなくて 迷い込んだニャンニャンニャン
Troublesome and unfavorable, strayed in, meow meow meow!
ここいらで落とした財布 誰か見ませんでした?
Has anyone seen the wallet I dropped around here?
馬鹿みたいについてないね 茶化してくハイウェイ・スター
We're ridiculously unlucky, teasing highway stars.
おう相棒 もう一丁 漫画みたいな喧嘩しようぜ
Hey partner, let's have another manga-like fight!
洒脱になんないくらいのやつをお試しで
Let's try out something so unrefined it's funny.
逃げ出したい夜の往来 行方はいまだ不明
The traffic of the night I want to run away from, my destination is still unknown
回り回って虚しくって 困っちゃったワンワンワン
Wandering around and feeling empty, I'm in trouble, bow-wow-wow
目指すのは メロウなエンディング
Aiming for a mellow ending
それは心臓を 刹那に揺らすもの
It's something that shakes the heart in an instant
追いかけた途端に見失っちゃうの
The moment you chase after it, you lose sight of it
きっと永遠が どっかにあるんだと
Surely eternity is somewhere out there
明後日を 探し回るのも 悪くはないでしょう
Searching around for the day after tomorrow isn't so bad, is it?
お前がどっかに消えた朝より どんな夜の方が まだましさ
Rather than the morning when you disappeared somewhere, a night like this is still better
肺に睡蓮 遠くのサイレン 響き合う境界線
Water lilies in the lungs, a siren in the distance, a boundary line resonating
愛し合う様に喧嘩しようぜ 遺る瀬無し引っさげて
Let's fight like we love each other, carrying our lingering sorrow
肺に睡蓮 遠くのサイレン 響き合う境界線
Water lilies in the lungs, a siren in the distance, a boundary line resonating
愛し合う様に喧嘩しようぜ 遺る瀬無し引っさげて
Let's fight like we love each other, carrying our lingering sorrow
たった一瞬の このきらめきを 食べ尽くそう二人でくたばるまで
Let's devour it together until we drop dead
そして幸運を ぼくに祈りを まだ行こう 誰も追いつけないくらいのスピードで
And wish us good luck... Let's keep going at a speed that nobody can catch up with
それは心臓を 刹那に揺らすもの
It's something that shakes the heart in an instant
追いかけた途端に見失っちゃうの
The moment you chase after it, you lose sight of it
きっと永遠が どっかにあるんだと
Surely eternity is somewhere out there
明後日を探し回るのも 悪くはないでしょう
Searching around for the day after tomorrow isn't so bad, is it?
稲妻の様に生きていたいだけ お前はどうしたい? 返事はいらない
I just want to live like lightning, what do you want to do? I don't need an answer
燃え上がる瓦礫の上に立っている いつからか何故なのか忘れたけど
Standing upon the burning wreckage surrounding me, though I've forgotten why or how long I've been here
息継ぎも出来ない炎の中では
Amidst these flames that choke my breath
探しても見つけても意味がないよ 壊せ超え過去のエクスタシー
No matter what I search for, it's all pointless! So break, and overcome past ecstasy
たとえ最悪でも未来を選べ「行こうぜ」
Even if it's the worst possible outcome, we've got to choose the future! Let's go.
ギリギリまで love forever 悶えるほど歌えば
Reaching the limits of love forever, if we can sing in agony together
魂はウロボロス巻き yeah それでもまだ叫べば
Our souls will coil into an Ouroboros! If we can still manage to scream then
生きることに焦がれれば その先は破滅の純情！
Seething with life beyond abound, what lies beyond is destructive purity!
吹き抜ける狂気を胸に走っている いつまでか何故なのか知らないけど
The madness blowing through my chest, though I don't know for how long or why
瞬きも出来ない速度の中では 嘆いても嘆いても虚しいだけ
Amidst speeds so intense I can't even blink, to cry out or express my woes is just futile
咆哮し弾け他人のエモーション たとえ最低でも自分を選べ
Roar aloud, burst out, our collective emotion! Choose yourself even in the worst reality
「飛ぶぞ」
I'm gonna fly.
スレスレまで love forever 狂えるほど踊れば
To the slimmest margin of love forever, if we can dance to the point of madness
魂は瘤倒と化し yeah それでもまだ動けば
Our souls will reach the critical point! If we can still manage to move then
光る空に届けば その先は破滅の純情！
Reaching that beyond shining star, what lies beyond will be a destructive purity!
純情！ 純情！ 純情！ 純情！ 純情！
Purity! Purity! Purity! Purity! Purity!
燃え上がる 瓦礫の上に 立っている
Standing atop burning rubble,
いつからか 何故なのか 忘れたけど
Though I've forgotten since when or why,
息継ぎも出来ない 炎の中では
Inside the flames where I can't even catch my breath,
探しても 見つけても意味がないよ
Searching or finding it has no meaning.
壊し超えろ 過去のエクスタシー
Break through and surpass past ecstasy,
たとえ最悪でも 未来を選べ
Choose the future, even if it's the worst.
「行・く・よ」
Here we go!
ギリギリまで love forever
Right to the limit, love forever,
悶えるほど歌えば
If you sing until you writhe in agony,
魂は渦を巻き yeah
Your soul swirls, yeah.
それでも まだ叫べば
Even so, if you still cry out,
生きることに焦がれれば
If you burn with a passion to live,
その先は 破滅の純情！
Beyond that lies the pure passion of ruin!
守る覚悟でなら
If you have the resolve to protect,
地獄を進め
Advance through hell.
「好・き・よ」
I love you.
何回目の last game over
How many times is this last game over?
全てをまた無くせば
If we lose everything all over again,
魂は乱麻を断ち yeah
Our souls sever the chaos, yeah.
生まれる日に戻れば
If we return to the day we were born,
消し去る日に眠れば
If we sleep on the day we fade,
その先は 微熱の純情！
Beyond that lies a feverish pure passion!
ギリギリまで love forever
Right to the limit, love forever,
悶えるほど歌えば
If you sing until you writhe in agony,
魂は輪廻に咲き yeah
Your soul blooms in reincarnation, yeah.
それでも まだ叫べば
Even so, if you still cry out,
生きることに躓けば
If you stumble in living,
その先は 破滅の純情！
Beyond that lies the pure passion of ruin!
ah 誰しもが baby
Ah, everyone, baby,
許してあげるわ カオスの絶頂！
I'll forgive you, the peak of chaos!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats resound,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the highest time and highest friends,
キラメキに乗って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
イエーイ！
Yeah!
覚えてるかな 最初の歌
Do you remember our very first song?
私の声が震えていた
My voice was trembling.
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなで掴んだ今日だよ
Is today we grasped together.
もっともっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
A heart accelerating more and more and more,
一緒にいくよ どこまでも
We'll go together, no matter where.
準備はOK?
Is everything ready?
ひらけ！夢のトビラを キラメキライダー☆
Open up! The door of our dreams, Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats resound,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the highest time and highest friends.
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me,
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ
I came here because I wanted to see you.
みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
Let's sing together, an endless melody,
キラメキに乗って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
届いてるかな 私の声
Is my voice reaching you?
届けたいのは 君の笑顔
What I want to deliver is your smile.
理想の遠さに悔しくて みんなで泣き笑ったね
Frustrated by the distance to our ideal, we cried and laughed together,
ぎゅっと全てを抱きしめて
Holding everything tight in our arms.
もっともっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
A heart accelerating more and more and more,
一緒に行くよ どこまでも
We'll go together, no matter where.
準備はOK?
Are you ready?
ひらけ！夢のトビラを キラメキライダー☆
Open up! The door of our dreams, Kirameki Rider☆
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいんだ
I want to play my feelings colorfully,
最高の場所 最高の仲間と
With the highest place and highest friends.
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm right here, it's not an illusion,
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart is dyed with happiness,
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って☆
Harmonies we pile up, clothed in sparkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな そんな願いはわがままだっていいでしょ?
I want to keep singing and dancing, is that okay?
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times and the best friends,
キラメキに乗っ て☆
ride on the twinkle☆
(イェーイ!)
(Yeah!)
覚えてるかな? 最初の一歩(懐かしいね)
Do you remember that very first step? (How nostalgic!)
私の声が震えていた(ほんの少し)
My voice was shaking (just a little bit).
あの日から続く未来は みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
The future leading from that day is today, grasped together with everyone.
もっともっともっともっともっと加速するハート
Faster, faster, faster, faster, accelerating heart!
(一緒に)行くよ どこまでも
(Together) Let's go, no matter where!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK?
(Are you ready?) Is everything OK?
ひらけ!! 夢のドビラを(1・2・3)
Open wide!! The doors of dreams (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキラライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times and the best friends,
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
we're right here because you found us!
君に会いたくてやって来たんだ みんなで歌おう
We wanted to see you so we came, let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗っ て☆
An endless melody, ride on the twinkle☆
届いているかな? 私の声(はっきり と)
Can you hear it? My voice (clear and distinct).
届けたいのは君に笑顔(そのスマイル!)
What I want to convey to you is your smile (that smile!).
理想の遠さに悔しくて
Frustrated by the distance to my ideals,
みんなで泣き笑ったね
we cried and laughed together, didn't we?
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっと全て抱きしめて
Hold on tight, hold on tight, embrace everything!
(一緒に)行こう どこまでも
(Together) Let's go, no matter where!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK?
(Are you ready?) Is everything OK?
すすめ!! 希望の道を(1・2・3)
Push ahead!! The road of hope (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキラライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play my favorite feelings colorfully,
最高の場所 最高のみんなと
in the best place, with everyone at our best.
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
We're right here, it's no illusion!
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So your heart will be dyed with happiness,
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って☆
layer our harmonies, wrapped in the twinkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing,
そんな願いわがままでもいいでしょ?
is such a wish and selfishness alright?
だって楽しすぎて! もうとまらない!!
Because it's too much fun! There's no stopping now!!
輝くステージで もっともっと!! (お願い) ずーーっと!!
On this shining stage, more and more!! (Please!) Forever!!
(オー!) (イェーイ!)
(Oh!) (Yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Happy, joyful, lovely—words alone aren't enough,
今も 今もある けど
they're here right now, but still,
ここにいるよ 私 ここにいるよ
We're right here, I'm right here,
君と同じ世界を見つめてめ
watching the very same world as you.
(行くよ!) (キラメキラライダー☆)
(Let's go!) (Kirameki Rider☆)
楽しかった、楽しかった!
That was so, so fun!
楽しかった!
It was so fun!
あの、もう大好きで、参戦している！
I mean, I just love it so much and I've been looking forward to this!
ねえ、素晴らしいね。先輩たちに
Right, right! That's wonderful. Senpais,
きていただけました！
we're so glad you came!
ありがとうございます、マリン、ちすせいちゃん…すせいちゃん！
Thank you, Marine, Chisuisei-chan... Suisei-chan!
そしてるしあちゃん！ありがとうございます先輩に
And Rushia-chan! Thank you so much, senpais,
来ていただきました！
for coming to join us!
本当に豪華なステージ！
Thank you for this gorgeous stage!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you!
ずっと大好き！
I love you guys so, so much!
大好きありがとう本当に！
We love you so much, thank you really!
あのみんな本当に忙しい中 集まってくれて、あの
Everyone gathered together in such busy schedules,
今回ね、記念ということで最初にね、最初のひももちろん来てくれて
this being an anniversary, you came for the very first day,
本当に時間をね、作ってくれました。
and really made the time for us.
みんな本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! We're the ones who should thank you!
本当に！
Thank you so much!
先輩たちと一緒のステージでね歌えるように私たちも頑張りながら！
We did our best so we could sing on the same stage with our senpais!
頑張って、ねえ歌ってください！
Yay! We sang it, please sing too!
がんばろう！ありがとうございます！
Good job! Thank you so much!
あ、時間があの、もうそろそろやばいということで
Ah, okay, okay, okay. Time is getting kind of dangerous,
はい！
Right!
それでは、めちゃめちゃ仲良しな私たち、こんなことない！
Alright, then let's all get cozy and close together!
ここにちょこんと、いっちゃおっか！ここにしちゃおう！
Let's all lie down right here!
お前たち帰るぞ！行こうよ！
Come on, we're taking you with us! Let's go!
はーい！はーい！
Yay! Yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あかねかなたの記念！
Thank you for Amane-kanata's anniversary!
ありがとうかなた！
Thank you, Kanata!
またね！またね！ありがとう！
See you again! See you again! Thank you!
またね！またね！
See you again! See you again!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えー、ということでね、素敵な先輩たちとも一緒に歌わせていただくことができました本当に！
And so, I was able to sing together with these wonderful senpais!
みんなのおかげです。ありがとうございます！
It's all thanks to everyone. Thank you very much!
えーっとですね、ここで、なんと！
And now, guess what?
一緒年記念と言えば…でででででででん！どん！どん！
If we're talking about the 1st anniversary... Tada!
活動一周年の記念ボイス、天音かなた、本日発売開始、えっと、9時45分からとかももう開始されておりますね。
Amane Kanata's 1st Anniversary Voice is now on sale starting January 2nd!
概要欄はちょっと更新できてないかもしれないんですけども、
The description might not be updated yet,
こちらブースでですね、発売されております。
but it's available on Booth!
今回はね、記念ボイスとともにグッズも2種類、おしお先生のね、見てこの素敵なね、とーとー推しに恵まれてに
This time, along with the anniversary voice, we have two types of goods!
泣き顔の推しと言われたあの、意味を重ね推しおママに、とうとうかなたの泣き顔を描いてもらいました！
"An Oshi who'll make you cry face to face"—that's what was said about this crying face!
これ以外にはね、あの推しおママが出してくれた本の中で、
Aside from this, in the book that Oshio-mama produced,
「さとみ」って言って泣いてるね、あの天音かなたしか泣いてるの描いたことないということで、本当にね、素敵なイラストを描いていただきました。
there's a page where she's crying and saying "Satomi,"
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そしてみんな覚えてる？5月とか6月くらいにさ、
And everyone remembers, right? Around May or June,
手裏剣のネックレスが欲しいって、みんな言ってたでしょ？ねえ！
you all kept saying "We want shuriken necklaces," right?
それをね今回叶えました！どどんっと！どどなんと！
Well, we made it happen this time, boom!
あ、出る？ん、出る？
Oh, is it out? Is it out?
あ、もう出ない？あ、出た出た出た。あ、これはね手裏剣じゃないですけども、
Ah, it's out! Ah, this isn't the shuriken, but
全部セット特典はですね、あの箔押し複製サインがね、こうやって、しかもちょっと、あの分かるかな？
the all-set bonus includes an Oshio-sensei-drawn "Amane Kanata"
さっきのね、泣いているお顔からちょっと、はにかんで笑っているというね、ちょっと、ま、僕らしいのではないかなという
replicated signature postcard, featuring a slightly smiling face right after crying,
あ、そうですね。こちらね全部セットの特典でございます。
Ah, that's right. These are the bonuses for the full set.
え、そしてですね、
And also,
みんな気になっているであろうね、天使の輪っかのね、
the angel ring accessory that everyone's probably curious about,
みんなと約束したので今回ね出してもらいました。
I promised everyone, so I had them make it.
どどん！
Ta-da!
こちらです！ネックレスとタッセルチャーム。
Here it is! A necklace and tassel charm.
えーとね、これね、チャームだけでも確かね買えるはずなので、
Um, you can actually buy just the charm separately, so,
あの、僕はね、オタクだったら、うーん、ネックレスは買えないけど、
um, if I were an otaku, I wouldn't buy the necklace, but
ちょっとしたシュリケンが欲しいと思ったときに変えるチャームも用意しました。
I prepared a charm too in case you just want a small shuriken.
みんなつけてくれる？ね、カワイイとかさ。
Will you all wear it? Like, "it's cute!"
しかもね、ゴールドとシルバーでね、どっちがいいかなって悩んだんだけど、
And with gold and silver, I agonized over which is better,
両方作ってもらいました！めちゃめちゃ無理を言って、
so I had both made! Going through so much trouble,
ありがとうございます本当に。
thank you so much, really.
よし、そして、どどん！
Alright, and then... ta-da!
あ、どどん！
Ah, ta-da!
はい、こちらがですね、一緒にグッズとしてついてくるタペストリーでございます。
Yes, this is the tapestry that comes with the merch.
いやもうさ、僕のタペストリー全部持っているっていう人はさ、部屋中かなたになってんじゃない？
Man, if you have all my tapestries, isn't your room entirely Kanata?
僕もサンプルでグッズいつもいただいてるんですけど、
I always get the merch as samples,
それを全部個々の部屋に上げてから個々の部屋が平民の部屋みたいになってるんだけどさ、
and I put them in all my rooms so they look like peasant rooms, but
今回のこれもね、あの飾るので、
I'll be displaying this one too.
そうするとね、間接的に霧子ともお揃いのことになりますので、
That way, you'll indirectly have matching items with Kiriko,
ぜひぜひこちらおじおじ先生の素敵なイラスト飾ってください。
so please, please display this wonderful illustration by Oji-oji-sensei.
と、いう感じで、オッケーかな。
So, yeah, with that, is that okay?
これでオッケーですね。
That's good.
えーと、ではですね、えーと、あと、もうこれラストスパパート、あと2曲になりました。
Um, well then, this is the last part, just two more songs left.
みんなへのね、気持ちをいっぱい込めて歌いたいと思います。
I want to sing with all my feelings for everyone.
それでは、最後の曲聞いてください。ほむら
Well then, please listen to the final song, Homura.
さよなら ありがとう 声の限り
"Goodbye," "Thank you," I say as loud as I can.
悲しみよりもっと大事なこと
Something more important than sadness,
去りゆく背中に 伝えたくて
I wanted to convey to your departing back,
ぬくもりと痛みに 間に合うように
so I can make it in time for the warmth and pain.
このまま続くと思っていた
I thought it would continue just like this,
僕らの明日を描いていた
picturing our tomorrows together.
呼び合っていた光がまだ 胸の奥に熱いのに
Even though the light we called out to is still hot deep in my chest,
僕たちは燃え盛る旅の途中で出会い
We met on our burning journey,
手を取りそして離した 未来のために
held hands, and let go for the sake of the future.
夢が一つ叶うたび 僕は君を想うだろう
Whenever a dream comes true, I will think of you.
強くなりたいと願い 泣いた
I cried, wishing to become stronger,
決意を餞に
taking that resolve as a parting gift.
懐かしい思いに囚われたり
Trapped in nostalgic memories,
残酷な世界に泣き叫んで
crying out in this cruel world,
大人になるほど増えて行く
the more I grow up, the more they increase.
もう何一つだって失いたくない
I don't want to lose even a single thing more.
悲しみに飲まれ落ちてしまえば
If I am consumed by sadness and fall into it,
痛みを感じなくなるけれど
I won't feel the pain anymore, but
君の言葉 君の願い
your words, your wish,
僕は守りぬくと誓ったんだ
I swore I would protect them to the end.
音を立てて崩れ落ちて行く
Crashing down with a loud sound.
一つだけのかけがえのない世界
The one and only irreplaceable world
手を伸ばし抱き止めた激しい光の束
Reaching out, I caught a bundle of intense light
輝いて消えてった未来のために
For the future that shone and faded away
託された幸せと約束を越えてゆく
I will go beyond the entrusted happiness and promises
振り返らずに進むから
I'll move forward without looking back,
前だけ向いて叫ぶから
shouting while facing only ahead.
心に炎を灯して 遠い未来まで……
Lighting a flame in my heart, to a distant future...
強くなれる理由を知った
I found out the reason I could become strong.
僕を連れて進め
Take me with you and push forward!
泥だらけの走馬灯に酔う
Intoxicated by the muddy revolving lantern,
こわばる心 震える手は
my stiff heart and trembling hands
掴みたいものがある
have something they want to grasp.
それだけさ
That's all there is to it.
夜の匂いに空睨んでも
Even if I glare at the night-scented sky,
変わっていけるのは自分自身だけ それだけさ
the only thing that can change is myself, that's all.
強くなれる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I found out the reason I could become strong, take me with you and push forward!
どうしたって! 消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what! Unfadeable dreams and an unstoppable present,
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can become strong for someone's sake—
ありがとう 悲しみよ
thank you, oh sorrow.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った 紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ!
Knocked down by the world, I learned the meaning of defeat. Bloom proudly, crimson lotus!
運命を照らして
Illuminate my destiny!
イナビカリの雑音が耳を刺す
The static of lightning pierces my ears,
戸惑う心 優しいだけじゃ守れないものがある
a bewildered heart—kindness alone cannot protect everything.
わかってるけど 水面下で絡まる善悪
I know that, but good and evil entangle beneath the surface,
透けて見える偽善に天罰
bringing divine retribution to transparent hypocrisy.
Tell me why, tell me why, tell me why, I don't need you
乱暴に引き裂かれた 毒だらけの道も
Even the venom-filled path that was brutally torn apart
本気の僕だけに現れるから 乗り越えてみせるよ
will appear only for my true self, so I will overcome it.
紅蓮の心臓に根を生やし この血に宿って
Planting roots in the crimson heart, dwelling in this blood,
人知れず儚い 散りゆく結末
a fleeting, unnoticed end scattering away,
無情に破れた 悲鳴の風吹く
ruthlessly torn, where the wind of screams blows.
誰かの泣き声 誰もが幸せを願ってる
Someone's weeping voice, everyone wishing for happiness—
どうしたって! 消せない夢も 止まれない今も
no matter what! Unfadeable dreams and an unstoppable present,
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can become strong for someone's sake—
ありがとう 悲しみよ
thank you, oh sorrow.
世界に打ちのめされて
負ける意味を知った
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ
運命を照らして
みんなありがとうございました！
今年もよろしくお願いします！
ありがとうございます！
えー応援の皆さん本当にたくさんの人にありがとうございます
みんなえみんなに会えてよかったと思っております
本当ありがとうございました！